

KTH Royal Institute of Technology

□ (+46) 72-3641828 | 🔀 gureya.daharewa@gmail.com | 🌴 gureya.github.io | 🖸 gureya | 🛅 gureya

Summary _

Currently Systems Researcher, interested in building system software for non-uniform memory access architectures and resource management in the cloud. 10+ years of experience working in diverse environments with a breadth of programs and technologies. Experienced in object-oriented (C++ & Java) and low-level C programming. Quickly learn and master new technologies if the need arises.

Professional Experience ____

INESC-ID, Instituto Superior Técnico, Portugal & KTH Royal Institute of Technology, Sweden

Stockholm, Sweden

October 2016 - present

RESEARCH ASSISTANT

• Dissertation: Resource Allocation for Data-Intensive Services in the Cloud.

- · OnlineElastMan: an "out-of-the-box" elasticity controller, which can be deployed and adopted by different storage systems without complicated tailoring/configuring efforts. The controller was implemented in Java & Matlab and was evaluated on a private cloud running OpenStack software stack and is openly available.
- BWAP: a novel bandwidth-aware page placement in NUMA systems. Implemented in C/C++ and open-sourced it.
- BALM: a QoS-aware memory bandwidth allocation technique for multi-socket architectures. Implementation done in C/C++ and will be readily available.

LOG Associates Nairobi. Kenva

CONSULTANT

March 2016 - September 2016

August 2013 - September 2016

- Lead consultant in the development of a Monitoring and Evaluation (M&E) System for the Kenya Cereal Enhancement Programme (KCEP).
- Designed and implemented Management Information System (MIS) for storing/analysing data and information relating to the programme, using Java Spring Framework & MySQL.

University of Nairobi Nairobi, Kenya

TUTORIAL FELLOW • Participation in the fields of teaching, research and development.

· Lecturing and project supervision for undergraduate and graduate students. Taught programming methodology and operating systems courses

Swedish ICT Stockholm, Sweden

RESEARCH ENGINEER

February 2015 - September 2015

- · Conducted research on elasticity management for cloud storage services. Main research topics included: Cloud computing, Online machine learning, and Time series analysis.
- Gain skills in Java, Linux, Matlab, OpenStack, and Cassandra.

C4DLab, University of Nairobi

Nairobi, Kenya

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

· Research, capacity building and training, systems design and development.

- Organized and participated in technological boot-camps, workshops, meetups, and seminars within Nairobi.
- Team Lead in developing system prototypes, notably among them were Games for Learning (G4L).

Cellulant Corporation

Nairobi, Kenya

August 2012 - March 2013

April 2013 - September 2013

- Requirements elicitation and planning, Solution analysis and design, Products development and Maintenance.
- Developed web applications using Yii PHP Framework, MySQL (LAMP), HTML/CSS/JavaScript.
- Worked on USSD applications and developed Java daemons for a payments ecosystem.

Education

Instituto Superior Técnico, Portugal & KTH Royal Institute of Technology, Sweden

Portugal/Sweden

October 2016 - present

DOCTOR OF SCIENCE (PHD) IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

- Advisor(s): Prof. João Pedro Barreto & Prof. Vladimir Vlassov.
- Thesis Title: Resource Allocation for Data-Intensive Services in the Cloud

DAVID GUREYA · CURRICULUM VITAE MARCH 18, 2021

Instituto Superior Técnico, Portugal & KTH Royal Institute of Technology, Sweden

Portugal/Sweden

ERASMUS MUNDUS MASTER (MSc) IN DISTRIBUTED COMPUTING

September 2013 - July 2015

- Advisor: Prof. Vladimir Vlassov.
- Grade: 17/20.
- Thesis Title: Self-trained Proactive Elasticity Manager for Cloud-based Storage Services [pdf]

University of Nairobi Kenya

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE (BSc) IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

- Grade: First Class Honours
- Thesis Title: Automatic language identification using N-Gram-Based Text Categorization.

October 2008 - August 2012

Skills

System research Extensive experience in performing research on system development.

Back-end Possess expertise in object-oriented (C++ & Java) and low-level C programming.

Distributed systems A firm foundation of distributed computing concepts, including cloud computing.

Full-stack Well-versed with full-stack knowledge including HTML/CSS/JavaScript, PHP, MySQL/MariaDB, NoSQL(Cassandra, Memcached); familiarity with scripting languages (Python, Shell).

Honors & Awards

INTERNATIONAL

2013 **Recipient**, Erasmus Mundus scholarship (academic-merit based, awarded each semester of MSc) Stockholm, Sweden
2016 **Recipient**, Erasmus Mundus fellowship for Joint Doctorate in Distributed Computing (EMJD-DC)
2016 **Finalist**, Best Poster Award at 2016 IEEE International Conference on Cloud and Autonomic Computing
(ICCAC)

Augsburg, Germany

Peer Reviewed Publications

2020	BWAP: Bandwidth-Aware Page Placement in NUMA, David Gureya, Joao Neto, Reza Karimi, Rodrigo	IPDPS'20
	Rodrigues, Paolo Romano, Pramod Bhatotia, Vivien Quéma, João Barreto and Vladimir Vlassov	IPDPS 20
2018	Asymmetry-aware page placement for contemporary NUMA architectures , David Gureya, Joao Neto,	SFMA'18
	Reza Karimi, Rodrigo Rodrigues, Paolo Romano, Pramod Bhatotia, Vivien Quéma, and João Barreto	
2018	Tackling memory asymmetry in NUMA architectures, David Gureya, Joao Neto, Reza Karimi, Rodrigo	INForum'18
	Rodrigues, Paolo Romano, Pramod Bhatotia, Vivien Quéma, and João Barreto	
2017	OnlineElastMan: Self-Trained Proactive Elasticity Manager for Cloud-Based Storage Services, Ying Liu,	Journal of Cluster
	Daharewa Gureya, Ahmad Al-Shishtawy and Vladimir Vlassov	Computing
2017	Profiling for Asymmetric NUMA Systems, David Gureya and João Barreto	EuroDW'17
2016	OnlineElastMan: Self-Trained Proactive Elasticity Manager for Cloud-Based Storage Services, Ying Liu,	ICCAC'16
	Daharewa Gureya, Ahmad Al-Shishtawy and Vladimir Vlassov	

Projects_____

2020	BWAP , A library for dynamic page placement in NUMA nodes.	github.com/epeec/BWAP
2017	MemoryTracer , An ISA-portable PIN tool for tracing memory accesses.	MemoryTracer
2017	OnlineElastMan , A Self-Trained Proactive Elasticity Manager for Cloud-Based Storage Services.	OnlineElastMan
2016	Forecasting, A set of Prediction algorithms for forecasting time series data.	forecasting